So I don't forget.
And I always open with this.
Today is February 9th, 2026.
And my name is Caitlin Sheets.
I'm here with AO.
We're conducting an interview with Evans Annex on the campus of Texas A&M University in College Station.
This interview is part of an oral history project documenting the experiences of Aggies for the 150th celebration of Texas A&M.
And do I have your consent to report?
Yes.
Just in case paper gets lost.
Awesome.
Thank you for joining me, and thank you for sharing your story with me.
Can I give a little bit of the dreaded question of like, tell me a little bit about yourself.
Like where you're born, your name's your parents.
Yeah, yeah.
So I was born on February 26, 2004.
So 22nd birthday, just around the corner.
I was born in Atlanta, Georgia.
My parents, they're from Nigeria.
They immigrated here.
My dad in 97.
My mom, I believe like 2000, 2003, around that time.
Yeah, and so I grew up most of my life in Atlanta up until the eighth grade.
My dad, he got a job at a Georgia Bush airport where he still works at the ASTSA.
And so he'd been working here maybe one or two years before, by the eighth grade, when we decided we were all going to move to Texas.
So ever since then, I've been living in Humble around the Houston area.
And so I've been living there ever since.
Awesome.
That's awesome.
What was your...
What made the family look from Georgia to Texas in general?
Um, so it's, it was mostly, like I said, my dad, uh, my dad, uh, he hadn't been working for a while up until then, just from the recession.
Um, and so there was, you know, opportunity and, you know, kind of the biggest sense of the word, uh, like I said, he'd been working there for one or two years.
And so we decided, you know, we just started a new life.
Yeah.
That's awesome.
I also forgot that that definitely is in the middle smack dab middle of recession time.
Yeah.
That's rough.
Um, so, um,
When you, what high school did you go to?
I went to Humble High School.
Humble High School, awesome.
So when you were in high school and you were looking at different universities, did you look at any other universities?
In principle, you always look into stuff like U of H, UT, all that type of stuff.
But for the most part, most of my high school experience, I'd say A&M was always at the top of my choice.
Oh, awesome.
Yeah.
So what kind of your thoughts of
this university before what was like enticing about it like uh basically the core um I was in JROTC in high school and so I was already exposed into that like military kind of ish environment um and you know I'm also a big history buff I always have been and so kind of I saw A&M as kind of like that kind of
pool of history that a lot of universities necessarily embrace or have.
And so it always kind of appealed to me in terms of like, you know, people always see it as like weird, but it was always, from my perspective, it was intriguing.
Right, yeah, absolutely.
Just for my curiosity, what's your, what's your, like, you said your interest in history, what's your interest?
So I grew, so for most of my life, I always was interested in like,
Soviet history, like the Eastern Bloc countries as well.
Over time, I grew out into more stuff like even my parents are from Nigeria and stuff like African history as well.
I'm a history buff, but in principle, Soviet Eastern Bloc kind of military history as well.
Yeah, absolutely.
That's awesome.
And I didn't ask this before, but what's your major?
I'm Bapol's major.
Oh, okay.
Awesome.
That's awesome.
what is also are you did you say you're a senior yeah congratulations i know that that has to feel really good yeah did you get your senior boots and everything yeah yeah yeah
It was a pretty cool experience just getting my senior boots.
I work with Leo at Hollix.
He's one of the boot makers.
I helped him make a website for one of his businesses.
I had the blessing of him being able to pay for my boots, which was pretty cool because those things aren't cheap at all.
Those things aren't cheap at all.
But just the experience of wearing boots, it feels like a culmination moment.
You always heard those clanking noises here in the hallway, across the quad, across the university.
But now being able to do the clanking, it's a pretty cool feeling.
It makes you feel powerful.
You stand up taller when you're in your boots.
It's definitely been a great experience so far.
Yeah.
So I've only been here like six months, like in Texas in general, six months.
Oh, really?
So the culture has been very unique to me.
Like, what things, from when you moved from Georgia to here, what were some things that surprised you about the culture of the world?
I'd say, I mean, Georgia is a small state.
Well, relatively small in terms of, like, the amount of major cities it has.
Atlanta's really the only one.
And so kind of like just being able to see, like, different parts of the state.
You know, Houston is one thing.
Then there's San Antonio.
Then there's Dallas.
Then there's Austin.
There's a lot of different things.
I'd say there's also like a more welcoming, like friendly culture.
I mean, even here with like the Howdy, but just, you know, that kind of friendly culture doesn't just exist like at A&M.
It's just pretty much across the state, I'd say.
I think that's pretty cool.
And kind of going back to what I said about the city, you know, everything's bigger in Texas.
You know, it's not really a cliche.
And so just like, it feels like a really more open, like bigger world.
Absolutely.
I agree with that.
It is mind-boggling just how large it is.
Like, you see it on maps, but then it actually experiences a whole other thing.
So I'm assuming you live on campus, right?
Do you remember those first few weeks?
What were your feelings?
What were you going through?
It was kind of like a really like I remember like coming on campus I'd come on campus a couple times before but just for FOW for that orientation week I remember when we like we're driving up near like the band field like the band they were doing they were doing like the drills because they came a week earlier and you they had their
you know the legendary kind of drum beat and you know my brother started laughing at me it's like well that's you that's you so it was kind of a cool kind of but it was kind of cool in general kind of feeling just being here being you know something I looked forward to for like four years in high school you know now I'm really doing it yeah um so you said you were in ROTC um how are you introduced to that um
In high school?
Yeah, yeah.
So it's crazy.
So the way it works is the way, so everyone has like PE credits obviously that they have to do.
It's always originally in PE.
And so, but you can take ROTC as kind of a substitute for that.
And so they usually come around maybe the first or second week of school just to see if anyone's interested.
And I figured because I always found PE to be kind of boring.
You know, never really like the craziest athletic guy was always on my phone.
And so I was like, at least I can save like battery power.
But you need moreover to, like I said, you know, I've always been like a history, military history buff.
So it wasn't really, it was kind of a no brainer for me too.
That makes sense.
Yeah.
So you've always been kind of interested in military.
Is that something that runs the family?
No, no, no.
I guess, I mean, the closest thing, Nigeria, they had, they have like, not the giraffe, but kind of a youth service corps.
And so my mom was in that, but that's pretty much it.
That's a really cool one.
Yeah.
So...
With your major, what is your hopeful job that you want to get?
So I want to go into cybersecurity.
I guess on the military side, I plan on going into the Coast Guard Reserves and doing kind of similar stuff.
Originally, I was kind of like a computer science kind of engineering major.
More or less my career goal hasn't changed, but I guess now it's more really focusing on cybersecurity and more so policy aspects as well.
Right, yeah, that makes sense.
That whole world to me is so confusing because I work with people who have been writing programs and stuff like that and they try to explain it to me.
I'm just like...
So you have to have a really great mind, and that just speaks a lot about you, though.
Yeah.
So you said...
Wait, you said cybersecurity and you wanted to go to... Coast Guard.
Thank you, Coast Guard.
Have you been down to Galveston and experienced that?
I've been down to Galveston, you know, just multiple times.
I've never been to the kind of Coast Guard base down there.
I've been talking to some people down there, too, about doing interviews and stuff.
And I've been trying to get, like, people's input of, like, oh, when I'm down there, what should I do?
What should I hit up first?
But...
It's interesting to me that everything kind of wraps back to that love of history to you.
What first got you interested in history?
I'll be honest, I think it just started early on.
I think early on in my life, I remember May 5th or 6th grade, we started talking about World War II and all that type of stuff.
I think it just sparked a point of interest.
Also around that time, I think I started watching more of like world news as well as current events.
You know, my mom used to make a joke, like when I'd get up in the morning, like to get before school, I'd just watch CNN or something like that.
So I think all that type of stuff, how current events intertwines with like world affairs and history, you know, now is appealing to me.
Yeah, very much so.
Yeah.
So, sorry, I have problems trying to like verbalize.
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
How do you, because a lot of history is really sad, how do you deal with some of those really emotional or sadder topics going through?
I think, I mean, it's weird because I don't really kind of interpret it through that way.
Obviously, like history, there's a lot of history that's sad, but you don't really, because it's past, you kind of interpret it kind of like it's a cool thing to learn about.
And if it is kind of like, you know, there's a lot of stuff that's, you know, Holocaust, slavery, whatever.
You interpret the lessons from those to apply to the modern area.
That's a really good point.
Yeah.
Those are some of the things that I like to ask.
I had a couple interviews with the actual history department, and so that was also a question to ask of, like, you're studying some of these really horrific things, how do you get through that?
And they actually mentioned that, too, about looking at the lessons and the kind of thing.
It's interesting to me.
So in university here, has there been any professors or lecturers that you're like, I want to do that, that's the kind of thing?
There have been kind of...
I'd say for the most part, no.
But I'd say there are a couple that I'd say I admire more so outside the professional setting.
I just admire them as people, both for the way they conduct their class, but also for what they do outside of class, if that makes sense.
Just how engaged they are with the university, engaged in their own professional lives, their own professional journey.
And honestly, I'd say I'm coming up to, now that I'm being a senior, I'm taking a lot of upper level classes, I'm finding a lot more of those.
That makes sense.
You get that personal.
Yeah.
Yeah, that's really cool.
Do you actually have, with being in the core, do you have time for
fun things do you have time for um like for yourself to have fun oh yeah oh yeah every everyone does yeah mostly yeah um so that very first year being in the core what were some things that you remember that really stuck out to you
I always remembered kind of like the lessons that, especially the senior class that I had when I was a fish, that they kind of always tried to impart on us.
I remember this one...
uh guy he's now in the army um doing finance work but he he always used to kind of like be the best be the best you could be um that always stuck with me uh in terms of quote um and like i said going back to like that senior class i always remember how they conducted themselves i always remembered you know once i become a senior you know that's how i hope to be so that's very true yeah
um and have you have you kind of taken on that role now since you are senior yeah i mean i hope i hope i've done a good job i mean it's halfway through the year but um yeah i'd say that i mean that literal role all seniors um if you know in the core that kind of leadership model there that's the point of inspiration um quite literally even with the boots um and so hopefully i've done that real well so yeah for sure um so what are some of the obviously there's many differences but
the way you view the Corps when you were in a profession versus now as a senior?
It's changed quite a bit while not changing at all, if that makes sense.
We've had four commandants for each year that I've been here.
So it's been kind of every year's a leadership change.
And then, of course, there's been transitions on the university level as well.
And so kind of the way the role...
or rather how the core is perceived in university and how the core behaves, and the university has changed both, in my opinion, for the better, as well as for the worse.
Something I'd say, a lot of people talk about, especially old acts, they would be like, you know, the course changes so much stuff, but, you know, I mean, it's just life.
Everything changes, nothing good doesn't change, so you just take,
by by may i won't be in the court so it won't matter to me what are your feelings on that on on grad on leaving the court oh i'm ready i'm ready yeah yeah yeah it's it's you get to that point it's like yeah you've done everything you needed to do you you hope along the way you made like friends and you you influence people for the better so that's really good looking at it because i know i would be
Horribly sad, but I'm really bad at goodbyes.
Yeah, yeah.
But I don't really think it's a goodbyes for you guys because ags are so, something I've learned is ags are so proactive and they stay in touch with each other.
So seeing that is like, wow, the community, that has to say something about this place.
Yeah, uh-huh.
Has there been anything surprising being a senior, whether that be school or core?
Uh...
Truth be told, I don't think there's anything surprising in the sense that I haven't heard of it before, like senioritis, all that kind of stuff.
Even in the core, like I said, I buy that time, I'm ready to go.
I have seen that for the past three years, so I'm really replicating the tradition, if you want to think of it like that.
Yeah, absolutely.
Speaking of tradition, that's a really good segue.
Some of the long-standing traditions, which ones that really mean something to you or stick with you?
I was always a...
a fan of muster mostly because I think it's like an incredible culminating point of the year especially being in the core but even if I wasn't in the core I think I would like muster because it's just a beautiful way to honor all Aggies who have passed during the past year
So far, the Mustard Speeches have been pretty excellent.
I really liked the one last year with General Downs.
It's always kind of like a warm feeling to be with people who are older than you.
I suppose people who probably aren't even thinking about college at that point, but all gathered to honor people in our community.
Truly.
I've never heard of any other university that does these types of traditions and still...
100 years later, they're still doing it.
Does that mean anything?
I know that's a silly question, but does that actually
mean anything to you and to you and your friends?
Oh, yeah.
I mean, the longevity of it is definitely, you know, it's great.
It's to know that, one, that it has been happening for 100 years, but also, like, more or less, as long as the university is alive and well, it will happen for 100 more.
And that, by the time I leave, you know.
Right.
leave this world, you know, I'll, I'll, I'll have a mustard, I'll have a mustard for friends, you know, it's definitely a beautiful feeling.
That's, that's a very good point.
Yeah.
Um, some, some things you don't like to think about in death, but hey, it's, it's kind of, um, not relaxing, but nice to know that you're going to be continuing on, your legacy is going to be continuing on, kind of thing.
Um, and so, you and your friends, your friend group right now, um, are,
Do you guys have any plans for after you graduate and you have that little bit of time?
I don't know if you do have that time.
Do you guys have anything planned?
In terms of just like... Just anything.
I don't know if you guys are taking a trip or a party.
One of my buddies in the Corps, he's going to get married this summer.
That would definitely be on the agenda.
Sure, yeah.
That's exciting.
So with the core, what are some things, because I try not to ask people, because you said there's some good and bad changes.
I'll stick to the good changes.
What are some of the good changes that you've seen?
Yeah, I'd say the core is definitely more visible on campus than it probably was my freshman year.
Discipline has probably been more set in stone.
I think going back to that first point, I think we're trying to
do a lot more stuff with the student body and as part of the student body as the keepers of the spirit and guardians of tradition um so whether it be through football or or anything else i think we're definitely more visible uh part of campus than probably we were in my uh my freshman year that makes sense yeah um and with you mentioned the every four years that has been changing um
the commandant has been changing.
With that, what are the kind of feelings?
Is there feelings of like instability or is there feelings of... Not instability per se.
I just say, you know, again, like rapid change, you know, everyone that comes in, they have their own agenda.
And so kind of just adapting to that as best as you can.
Very good.
What are some traditions in the core that you think you'll continue on in your life?
Or it doesn't even have to be tradition, it could just be habits or anything like that.
I'd say just like good time management.
Good time management.
I think for a lot of people, that's the main thing they'll take from the core.
Because you do have to, you know, like I said way early on in the interview, you know,
You can't have fun, but part of the sacrifice is that you have to have good time management in order to make room for that fun.
So definitely, that's something I'll take away from the court, both in the civilian sector and in the military.
For sure.
And with the field that you're going into with cybersecurity, what's your...
You said you want to work with the military, obviously, but do you have, like, a dream position or a dream job?
So, yeah, I want to serve as a cyber officer.
So, still trying to figure out what that necessarily means.
But mostly, you know, kind of cyber intelligence and stuff like that.
For sure.
I feel like that field is booming.
Yeah.
So, with the...
Okay, your thoughts on the core and would you have ever considered not joining?
Okay, this is kind of silly, but would you ever consider not joining before or was that like an always?
You mean like before?
Oh yeah, so I think maybe it was like
in between my junior and senior year when I was like, okay, now you have to really make a choice.
I was like, because I think I was always dead set on doing ROTC, because I did ROTC in high school, but I was like, do I really want to join a core?
But eventually I just, you know, came around to accept again.
It was like, this will be cool.
This is something that everyone's done.
I think it's just those type of, you join new organization, new institution type anxieties that, you know, they may be there for like five minutes, but then, you know, they dissipate.
We have.
That makes sense.
Yeah.
And segueing a little bit more.
So how has the core impacted your experience overall in college?
just whether that be class or just the social aspect.
I mean, it's basically shaped more or less kind of my entire college experience because like, you know, you mentioned class.
I mean, I go to class in uniform, you know, that's a very visible part of your university life.
And I say it's done so for the better.
It makes you, it's made me unique.
It's made me kind of stand out above the rest in a positive way.
And then, you know, it allows for a lot of, like, networks to be created.
I've gotten opportunities and been in spaces I probably wouldn't be in because of my experience in the core.
So I'm definitely grateful.
I don't think, like I said, I don't think I'd have it any other way.
Right, yeah.
Talk a little bit about that.
What are some experiences that kind of opened up to you because of it?
Yeah, there's been a litany of stuff.
I can just think about, as a matter of fact, the reason I got connected with this interview is because last summer I participated in the Army 250 parade in Washington, D.C. One of the cadre, he referred the people who participated to this interview.
But yeah, I got to go to Washington, D.C.
I've been there before, a couple times before, but I never, like, at this level, like, for a world audience in front of the Commander-in-Chief.
So, you know, stuff like that does a pretty cool experience.
You get to be around, you know, like, the networking aspect, being around people from the Citadel, VMI, other universities, West Point, being around, like, Big Army.
So it was a pretty cool experience.
Yeah.
So that completely blew my mind that
that you were in, that you were actually in that.
What were some of the feelings and some of the things that you saw that really are going to stick with you for life for the parade that you did?
Honestly, like, just, like, the march down to when we did, when we, you know, do the, like, salute for the president, it's just, like, an unreal experience.
Because you see all these people, like, Trump, J.D.
Vance, Margaret Ruby, all these politicians in, like, TV for so long that you forget to actually... Real people.
And so, like, when we...
We were approaching the reviewing stand.
He begins to stand up.
I was like, oh shit, this is real.
I'll never forget that moment.
That was a pretty cool moment.
That's really cool.
Somebody sent me a picture of you guys doing the march.
That's so interesting.
That's a part of history now.
Yeah.
yeah so because we're in the core we never had like such extensive practice because we don't need it we march all the time
Whereas perhaps other like active duty units, they probably need more like actual, you know, specific drill practice.
So we got a notification a couple weeks earlier.
Usually it's ROT, they gave ROTC, people who are in Army ROTC preference, and then they, you know,
opened it up for the rest of the Corps.
And so I jumped on that opportunity.
We had a bunch of, we didn't, you know, because we were all, it's over the summer, so it's in June, so everyone's everywhere.
Some people are at home.
I was in College Station over the summer, you know, working.
And so,
We all had to prepare ourselves in our own different way.
And then once we got there to Washington, we first went to housing.
We were lucky because we got maybe one or two days to really explore the city.
Next day, we had kind of general rehearsals.
Not like through, we didn't do the whole parade route, but just like general marching rehearsals in our blocks, just so that we know what to do and we're all squared away.
Awesome.
So when you're actually doing the marching, marching down, what was going through your head?
I was just trying to stay locked in, trying not to look a fool.
We marched from the area where everyone was just based all the way through the parade route.
It was quite a while.
Sorry.
Three or four miles.
And so it was quite a while until we had to break.
But yeah, we just marched.
And then, you know, just kind of, because usually we march with like Jody's, we call them like songs and stuff, but we kind of kept it until the end.
And so it was just like, please just stay in step.
You know, don't look a fool, you know.
But it was kind of weird because, you know, there were Aggies there, too.
And so they'd see us.
They'd be like, you know, gig him, Aggies.
You do want to whoop, but you can't.
But that was pretty cool.
Yeah.
That's something that I find interesting.
I've heard a lot of stories about people recognizing other Aggies for the rings and just out in public.
Have you had those kind of moments of not even being connected to the university, but out in public, someone recognizes you as an Aggie?
So weird because I don't have, I just got my ring like last November.
So I've had those kind of Aggie ring moments.
But definitely like I've seen people like A&M just recognizing.
And then sometimes we just get in conversation, you know, just talk about where we come from.
I've done events.
You know, I'm a member of the Corps of Color Guard.
And so I've done events, you know, say at the Houston Rodeo and stuff.
And the organizer, you know, they're a former cadet, you know, that will get to chopping it up.
You know, what was it like in the Corps and stuff?
What is your outfit?
So those things are pretty cool.
It's pretty cool.
As you said, the doors open kind of thing and people naturally leave.
So what are some...
or things that you would tell an incoming freshman?
I'd say just kind of relax.
Just take everything as it is.
I remember when I first, so over the summer when you do your NSC, your new student conference, they had me do a brief mini NSC with the Corps where you get to pick up some of your basic boots, your shoes as well.
And so I went into the distribution center where we got our uniforms.
And I remember, like, she was the lady.
She was, like, maybe a senior cadet just working over the summer.
I remember her.
I remember she was telling this other guy.
He was asking for, like, advice.
She was, like, don't take it all seriously.
Don't take it all seriously.
I mean, she still works here.
I never told her that.
But I still remember it when she said it.
You know, now coming back to it, just, like,
That's really the only advice I'd give is just don't take it all too seriously.
I think that's important.
Are there any old traditions that you think should be brought back?
I'm actually not sure of all of them, but any old traditions that you wish were still around?
Nothing comes to mind.
I don't want to be honest.
That's fair.
I'm still also learning the history.
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
There's a lot.
There's a lot of different...
There's so much to go through.
Different eras.
Is there any... We don't have classwork and stuff.
As you said, you talked a little bit about professors that kind of stuck out to you.
Are there any that...
you want to emulate going forward or that you're like or even that you want to get like hit up and get close to now that you're graduating yeah so there are a couple that you know I still kind of keep in touch with and it's not just professors but even like TAs as well um that that you know we have kind of similar interests and stuff um there's this one professor who he was very just plain cave
you need anything, you know, lay me any kind of, I have a bunch of connections, you know, don't be afraid to hit me up.
So I think that's a pretty cool part of the Aggie Network.
That's not, because they might not even be Aggies too.
So I think it's a pretty cool part of the Aggie Network.
That's very true.
It's nice to know that's something I took back out there.
What is you're most excited for now that you're here at the end?
uh just getting out just getting out and actually like going to the big world going working stuff like that that's so valid yeah yeah um and as you prepare to um to leave here um what are your thoughts and feelings on this university they're incredibly warm i'd say you know the best series of my life so far
I'd say they gave me the best years of my life so far.
And I'd say, like I said earlier, I couldn't imagine my life outside of it.
Outside of it.
Yeah.
Oh my.
Of course, of course.
I have some legacy questions from, his name is Haskell Monroe.
He's a historian.
He also still works here.
He's been working for years and years.
So the legacy questions I had is, say someone gave you a million dollars, but you had to put it to some part of this university, what would it go to?
That's a good question.
All of it would have to go to some part.
I'd say... That's a good question.
I never thought about it.
I'd say, I'd say probably Heldenfields.
I'd better say Heldenfields.
That's a pretty, that's a pretty interesting building.
Yeah.
It's kind of rough.
It's rough.
It's rough in there.
You could use a facelift.
Yeah.
That's fair.
That's very fair.
And something that I'd like to ask as well is what makes an Aggie to you?
Like, from any other...
university or from any other person in the corner, what specifically makes an Aggie?
I don't think it necessarily is about what makes an Aggie, but I think it's about what
what an Aggie subscribes to, which is the core values.
And so I think, and that's kind of subscription to the core values makes you an Aggie, albeit, you know, anyone in that case could be an Aggie.
But, like, I think, yeah, I think there's nothing specific, like, to A&M that I think necessarily is worth saying, oh, yeah, this makes me an Aggie.
But I think it's definitely the...
larger high-level, the more broader core values and the kind of disciplined adherence to them that really stand out in terms of what this university produces.
Yeah.
That is something that I very quickly learned is the core values and that it's not just talk, it's people around here actually do it.
They walk the walk.
That's super impressive to me.
And another one is, as I said, the feelings that you have in your heart for this university, if you could express that, what would that be?
I'd say ADM is an institution that, in a world of chaos, you can always go back to it and say, at least there's hope.
As simple as that sounds, I think that's pretty much how I'd say it.
In a world where it feels like everything's just fucking burning down, there's one constant.
And everything will change.
It changes for the better.
is to re-adhere to, like I said, the core values that it promotes.
That makes sense.
And that's really nice.
I don't think that's silly at all, but I think that's very true.
And my last question before I ask you some, I'm just saying the same thing, but my last question is, if you could give advice to the leaders of this university, what would that be?
I'd say...
I'd say, I'd say, remember where you came from.
This is, I guess this is more so for the Aggies that work, but even for the non-Aggies, you know, remember where you came from.
Don't forget, my mom always used to tell me, don't forget the son of who you are.
So, you know, just remember your roots, and I think that should be the more guiding, that will guide you to the correct path.
Awesome, yeah.
Was there any...
topics or things that you wanted to cover that I didn't touch on at all.
OK, awesome.
Thank you so much for doing this.